Some people learn the hard way.
Bad Education is a drama, crime, history film directed by Cory Finley.
A superintendent of a school district works for the betterment of the student’s education
when an embezzlement scheme is discovered, threatening to destroy everything.
Frank Tassone, played by Hugh Jackman.
Pam Gluckin, played by Allison Janney.
Rachel Bhargava, played by Geraldine Viswanathan.
Nick Fleischman, played by Alex Wolff.
Kyle Contreras, played by Rafael Casal.
Thomas 'Tom' Tuggiero, played by Stephen Spinella.
Bad Education is a 2019 American crime drama film directed
by Cory Finley and written by Mike Makowsky.
It is based on the 2004 New York magazine article "The Bad Superintendent" by Robert Kolker,
about the true story of the largest public school embezzlement in American history.
It features an ensemble cast including Hugh Jackman, Allison Janney, Geraldine Viswanathan,
Alex Wolff, Rafael Casal, Stephen Spinella, Annaleigh Ashford and Ray Romano.
Set in the Long Island village of Roslyn in the early 2000s, the film
tells the story of school district superintendent Dr.
Frank Tassone (Jackman) who, along with assistant superintendent Pam Gluckin (Janney) stole millions of dollars
from their wealthy public school district, and together attempted to cover up the embezzlement.
The screenwriter, Makowsky, briefly met Tassone as a child before the
scandal broke and attended Roslyn High School in the late 2000s.
Bad Education made its world premiere on September 8, 2019, at the Toronto
International Film Festival and was broadcast on HBO on April 25, 2020.
It was well received by film critics, with particular praise for Makowsky's
screenplay, Finley's direction, and Jackman's and Janney's performances.
At the 72nd Primetime Emmy Awards, the film won for Outstanding Television Movie and Jackman received a
nomination for Primetime Emmy Award for Outstanding Lead Actor in a Limited or Anthology Series or Movie.
The film explores themes of based on true story, long island, new york,
school, embezzlement, based on magazine, newspaper or article.
The tone is emotional.